RG 004:040, East Granby Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
East Granby Probate Court records
1865-1976
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate (East Granby)
17.5 cubic feet
Record books, 1865-1972; Probate files, 1865-1976.
RG004_040
2011-093 and 2011-094
Historical Note
East Granby, Hartford County, Town established in June 1858, Parent Town: Granby and Windsor Locks
The East Granby Probate District was constituted July 4, 1865, from the Granby Probate District. The East Granby Probate District merged with the Suffield Probate District on January 3, 2007, and later with the Bloomfield and Windsor Locks Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Tobacco Valley Probate District which serves the municipalities of Bloomfield, East Granby, Suffield, and Windsor Locks.
Town of East Granby, Probate District chronology:
June 1858 - July 3, 1865, Granby District
July 4, 1865 - January 4, 2011, East Granby District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Tobacco Valley District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, Volumes 1-11, 1865-1972. There are 2 volumes numbered 7 and a separate bond volume numbered 1. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1865-1976. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered consecutively from 1 to 11. There are 2 volumes numbered 7. There is a separate bond volume numbered 1.
Probate Files are arranged as received from the probate court.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. Note: CSL does not hold any original record books. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 2011-094.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- East Granby
Places:
East Granby (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files from 1921-1976 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
Accession 2011-093, Record books, 1865-1972, and Accession 2011-094, Probate files, 1865-1976, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1 and 3, 1865-1955, were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The record books in Accession 2011-093 and the probate files in Accession 2011-094 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on January 10, 2011.
Container List
- Record books, 1865-1972; 7.5 cubic feet (13 volumes); 2011-093
  - Records, 1865-1888 (Volume 1)
  - Orders and decrees, 1887-1902 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1888-1955 (Volume 3)
    On spine: "Manuscript"
  - Orders and decrees, 1902-1918 (Volume 4)
  - Orders and decrees, 1919-1937 (Volume 5)
  - Orders and decrees, 1937-1950 (Volume 6)
  - Orders and decrees, 1949-1975 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1947-1968 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1953-1960 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1957-1964 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1965-1969 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1964-1972 (Volume 11)
  - Bonds, 1882-1962 (Volume 1)
- Probate Files, 1865-1976; 10 cubic feet; 2011-094
  - Probate files, 1865-1976 (Box 1-10)